Guide to the Lee J. Cronbach Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2008-033
  - Lee J. Cronbach writings (in reprint, typescript, and other formats):
    - Can a Machine Fit an Applicant to Continuing Education?, publication 1969 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - A Case Study of the Split-Half Reliability Coefficient, reprint 1946 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Clothes Don't Make the Emperor, statement prepared for SUSE faculty panel (on research), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Coefficient Alpha and the Internal Structure of Tests (appearing in column "Citation Classics" March 27, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Comments on Mastery Learning and its Implications for Curriculum Development, photocopy of pre-print, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Compatibility paper (several versions), 1953, with related correspondence 1952-53 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Concept Attainment with Probabilistic Feedback, reprint 1956 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Conceptual and Methodological Problems in Interpersonal Perception, prepublication report, 1954, and reprint 1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - A Consideration of Information Theory and Utility Theory as Tools for Psychometric Problems, Technical Report Number 1, College of Education, University of Illinois, November 1953 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Construct Validation after Thirty Years, computer printout and proof, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Construct Validity in Psychological Tests, reprint 1955 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - The Counselor's Problems from the Perspective of Communication Theory, publication 1955 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Correlation between Persons as a Research Tool, typescript 1951 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Course Improvement through Evaluation, reprint 1963 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Cue-Response Correlations in the Attainment of a Scalar Concept, reprint 1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Current Ideas on Educational Evaluation, lecture presented at the College of Education, Bangkok, Feb. 22, 1968; photocopy of typescript and Thai publication (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Masters for reproducing CGNR (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Dependability of Behavioral Measurements – errata (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Design Study for Sonar Pitch Memory Test, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Designing Educational Evaluations – translation (or presentation of ) by Jean Cardinet, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Les Deux Disciplines de la Psychologie Scientifique, reprint 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Dissent from Carver, in "Comment," American Psychologist, photocopy, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Education Approaches Period of Constructive Change, reprint 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Educational Psychology Bulletin, No. 1-4 – master set, 1963-64 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Educational Reform in Japan, reprint 1948 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Efficiency of Multiple-Choice Tests as a Function of Spread of Item Difficulties, reprint 1952 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Equity in Selection – Where Psychometrics and Political Philosophy Meet, reprint 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - On Estimates of Test Reliability, reprint 1943 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Estimation of the Specific Reliability of a Test or Rater, mimeographed paper, Bureau of Educational Research, U. of Illinois, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Estimation of Variance Components in Reliability Studies, reprint 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Les Exigences de la Validation des Techniques Projectives, reprint 1955 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - An Experimental Comparison of the Multiple True-False and Multiple Multiple-Choice Tests, reprint 1941 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Experimental Design for Research in Psychotherapy, reprint 1952 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Exploring the Wartime Morale of High-School Youth, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Extensions of Personnel Selection Theory to Aspects of Minority Hiring, IFG Project Report No. 81-A2, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Evaluation Conference, University of Illinois – topical outline and reference list, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Evaluation for Course Improvement, reprint 1964 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Five Decades of Public Controversy over Mental Testing, reprint 1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Five Perspectives on Validity Argument, prepublication copy, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Four Psychological Bulletin Articles in Perspective, reprint 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Fourteen Points paper (Toward a Reformation in Evaluation: Fourteen Points), original typed outline, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Further Evidence on Response Sets and Test Design, reprint 1950 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Generalizability of Scores Influenced by Multiple Sources of Variance, technical report 1961 and journal reprint 1965 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Generalizability of Stratified-Parallel Tests, reprint 1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Generalized Psychometric Theory Based on Information Measure, A Preliminary Report, University of Illinois, March 1952 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Guidance and Testing, Voice of America Forum Lectures pamphlet 13 (no date) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Heredity, Environment, and Educational Policy, reprint 1969 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Homogeneity as a Tool for Test Evaluation, draft of presentation for APA symposium, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - How Can Instruction Be Adapted to Individual Differences, mimeographed copy of chapter from unnamed book (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - How People Learn from Mass Media, summarized account from conference (?), 1950 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - How Promising is the Assessment Approach?, typescript 1950 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - How to Determine and Interpret Test Homogeneity, mimeographed conference paper, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Howe We Should Measure "Change"-Or Should We? – technical report, 1969, and reprint, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - In Praise of Uncertainty, reprint of chapter from New Directions for Program Evaluation: Standards for Evaluation Practice, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Individual Differences in Learning Ability as a Function of Instructional Variables, interim report, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Individual Differences in Learning to Reproduce Forms: A Study in Attention, reprint, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Integrated Studies of Measurement Theory, Progress Report USPHS Grant M-1839, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Intellectual Progress Variables, typescript with hand-written tables, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Intelligence? Creativity? A Parsimonious Reinterpretation of the Wallach-Kogan Data, reprint 1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Interdisciplinary Colloquium on Mathematics in the Behavioral Sciences, Colloquium Document No. 12a, 1963/64 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Internal-Consistency Reliability Formulas Applied to Randomly Sampled Single-Factor Tests: An Empirical Comparison, reprint 1962 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Interpretation of Reliability and Validity Coefficients: Remarks on a Paper by Lord, reprint 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Intraclass Correlation as an Approximation to the Coefficient of Generalizability, reprint 1964 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Investigation of the Character and Properties of Assumed Similarity Measures (Project on social perception and Group Effectiveness) Technical Report No. 7, Feb. 1953 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Issues Current in Educational Psychology, conference paper 1962 and journal reprint 1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Judging How Well a Test Measures, offprint from conference 1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - The Learning Process and Text Specifications, Chapter IV, photocopy from book published in 1955 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Learning Research and Curriculum Development, reprint, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Lee J. Cronbach," Revue de Psychologie Appliquée, Juillet 1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - The Logic of Experiments on Discovery, book chapter in English and Japanese (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - The Meanings of Problems, photocopy of book chapter (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Measured Mental Abilities: Lingering Questions and Loose Ends, photocopied chapter from Human Diversity: Its Causes and Social Significance, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Measuring Knowledge of Precise Word Meaning, typescript article (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Measuring Students' Thinking about a Presidential Election, reprint 1941 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Mental Tests and the Creation of Opportunity, reprint 1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Mental Test Theory and Decision Theory, in Psychological Measurement Theory, Proceedings of the NUFFIC International Summer Session in Science, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - A Model for Studying the Validity of Multiple-Choice Items, reprint 1965 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - A Moderate View: Response to Ellis and Blustein, publication 1991 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Nationality Preferences of Japanese Students after World War II (By Koji Sato and Fuyuo Nakano, edited for publication by LJC) 1948 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - The New Definition of Aptitude, typescript paper 1966 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - The New Demands on the Curriculum Evaluator, lecture given at Stanford University (mimeographed), 1965 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - A Note on Negative Reliabilities, reprint 1954 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Note on the Multiple True-False Test Exercise, reprint 1939 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Notes on Choice of Science and Engineering as a Career (notes for an informal talk to the Businessmen's Advisory committee of the Illinois State Chamber of Commerce) 1959 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - On the Design of Educational Measures, reprint 1976 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - The Overemphasis on R&D in Federally Supported Research, publication 1966 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Pattern Tabulation": A Statistical Method for Analysis of Limited Patterns of Scores, with Particular Reference to the Rorschach Test, reprint 1949 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Performance on a Concept-Attainment Task with Scaled Cues. II. Probabilistic Feedback. Technical Report, University of Illinois, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Personality and Intellectual Functioning in Graduate Students, mimeographed conference paper, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Personality in the Research Worker: Observations on Graduate Students, typescript 1949 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Prediction of Success in Architecture, mimeographed conference paper, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Proposals Leading to Analytic Treatment of Social Perception Scores, photocopied chapter from unnamed book (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Prospects for a Psychometric Theory Based on Utility Measure, conference paper, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Prudent Aspirations for Social Inquiry, reprint of chapter from The Social Sciences: Their Nature and Uses, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Psychological Aspects of the Technical Vocabulary of Elementary Algebra. I. Measurement of concept knowledge II. Learning and retention of vocabulary. MA thesis, UC, July 1936, typescript (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Psychological Background for Curriculum Experimentation, mimeographed conference paper, 196- (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Psychological Issues Pertinent to Recent American Curriculum Reform, mimeographed symposium paper, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Psychology, Education, and the Natural Welfare, Test Service Bulletin No. 90, ca. 1958 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Pupil-Morale after One Year of War, reprint 1943 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Pupil Perceptions of Teachers: A Factor Analysis of "About My Teacher," reprint 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Quantal and Graded Analysis of Dosage-Effect Relations, reprint 1961 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Reliability as Generalizability: Internal-Consistency Formulas Derived from a Stratified-Sampling Assumption, research report May 1960 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Reliability Formulas for Independent Decision Data When Reliability Data are Matched, reprint 1960 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Reliability on Ratio Scores (and follow-up Note on), reprint 1941 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Remarks to the New Society, photocopy of published item, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Requirements for Validation of Projective Techniques, typescript paper, 195- (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Report on a Psychometric Mission to Clinicia, reprint 1954 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Research Conference on Learning and the Educational Process at Stanford University, June 22-Judy 31, 1964, Cooperative Research project No. F-109 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Research Conference on "Learning by Discovery" New York City, January 27-28, 1965, Cooperative Research project No. F-064 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Research on Personality at Maudsley Hospital, ONR London, Technical Report ONRL-19-56, typescript 1956 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Research Worker's Treasure Chest, photocopy of published article 1984 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Response Sets and Test Validity, reprint 1946 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Response Styles – bibliography and notes, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - The Role of the University in the Improvement of Education, 1966 – as published by Yeshiva University and in Phi Delta Kappan (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - The Scholars Look at the Schools, a Report of the Disciplines Seminar [LJC was one of the participants], 1962 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Selection and Training, reprint 1949 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Selection Theory for a Political Work, project report and copy of published version, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Signal/Noise Ratio in the Comparison of Reliability Coefficients, reprint 1964 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Signs of Optimism for Intelligence Testing, publication 1986 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Similarity between Persons and Related Problems of Profile Analysis, University of Illinois Technical Report No. 2, April 1952 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Social Inquiry in the Public Interest, The Fourth Vernon-Wall Lecture, pamphlet 1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Social Inquiry by and for Earthlings, photocopy of book chapter, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Statistical Methods Applied to Rorschach Scores: A Review, pamphlet 1949 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Statistical Methods for Multi-Score Tests, reprint 1950 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Statistical Tests for Moderator Variables: Flaws in Analyses Recently Proposed, reprint 1987 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Stereotypes and College Sororities, reprint April 1944 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - A Strong Model for Analyzing Nonrandom Experiments, draft of research report, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Studies of Acquiescence as a Factor in the True-False Test, reprint 1942 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Studies of the Group Rorschach in Relation to Success in the College of the University of Chicago, reprint 1950 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Suggestions Regarding a Possible Measure of Personality: The Squares Test, reprint 1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Test Validity as a Function of Item Difficulty, outline of conference paper, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Text in Use (chapter VII of a book), photocopy 1955 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Robert L. Thorndike, obituary by LJC, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Time-Limit Tests: Estimating Their Reliability and Degree of Speeding – reprint 1941, notes, and text for a reconsideration, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Transfer of Training, Manuscript prepared for the Encyclopedia of Educational Research – mimeographed text 1950 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - The True-False Test: A Reply to Count Etoxinod, reprint 1940 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Two Conceptions of Learning, Education, Evaluation – outline, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Two Disciplines of Scientific Psychology, reprint 1957 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Tyler's Contribution to Measurement and Evaluation, reprint with related correspondence 1986 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - A Validation Design for Qualitative Studies of Personality, reprint 1948 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Validation of Educational Measures, typescript and reprint, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - A Valedictory: Reflections on 60 Years in Educational Testing, publication 1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Validity of Inference in Applied Social Research – proofs in English, Swedish reprint, and related correspondence, 1977-80 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Validity on Parole: How Can We Go Straight?, typescript and reprint, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Vocabulary, notes on, undated (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - The Wartime Morale of Youth – An Analysis of the School's Problem, reprint 1942 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - What the School Can do to Build Morale, typescript (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - What Price Simplicity?, publication 1983 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - What Research Says about Programed [sic] Instruction, reprint 1962 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Year-to-Year Correlations of Mental Tests: A Review of the Hofstaetter Analysis, photocopy of article 1967 (Box 7, Folder 26)